Guide to the El Malcriado: Spanish language newspaper, 1964-1975
El Malcriado: Spanish language newspaper,
1964-1975
Special Collections M0882
Keene, Calif
3 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Issues of El Malcriado collected by Father Victor P. Salandini. Some issues are in Spanish, with occasional issues in English.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Please request the materials at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Louise M. Roccoforte, 1996
Scope and Content of Collection
Issues of El Malcriado collected by Father Victor P. Salandini. Some issues are in Spanish, with occasional issues in English.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
United Farm Workers; Agricultural Laborers; Mexican Americans--California--Newspapers; Trade-unions
Container List
- El Malcriado, no 1 - 26, 1964 - 1965, more than half of the issues are xeroxes (Box 1)
  In Spanish.
- El Malcriado, no. 27 - 52, 1966 (Box 2)
  These issues are primarily in Spanish, though some English-language duplicates exist.
- El Malcriado, no. 53 - 65, 1967 Jan. 3 - 1967 July 19 (Box 2)
  Issues no. 61 is missing; nos. 54-57 are in Spanish; nos. 53, 54, 57-65 exist in English language copies as well.
- El Malcriado, no. 66, 1967 Aug. 16 (Box 3)
- El Malcriado, Vol. 2, nos. 1 - 20, 1968 Feb. 21 - 1968 Dec. 15 (Box 3)
  Volume 2, no. 17 is missing. Most of the issues are in English.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 2, nos. 21-22, 1969 Jan. 1 - 1969 Jan. 15 (Box 4)
  Issues are in English. Note: the issue marked Vol. 2, no. 22 is different than the subsequently-described Vol. 2, no. 22. Two issues share the same number.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 2, nos. 22-24, 1969 Feb. 1 - 1969 Feb. 15 (Box 4)
  Issues are in English. Note: the issue marked Vol. 2, no. 22 is different than the previously-described Vol. 2, no. 22. Two issues share the same number.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 3, nos. 1-17, 1969 Mar. 1 - 1969 Dec. (Box 4)
  Issues are in English. Vol. 3, nos. 18 & 19 are missing
- El Malcriado, Vol. 3, nos. 20-27, 1970 Feb. - 1970 June 15 (Box 4)
  Issues are mostly in English.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 4, nos. 1-3, 1970 June 15 - 1970 July 15 (Box 4)
  Issues are mostly in English. Note: the issue marked Vol. 4, no. 3 is different than the subsequently-described Vol. 4, no. 3. Two issues share the same number.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 4, nos. 3-14, 1970 Aug. 1 - 1971 Feb. 1 (Box 4)
  Issues are mostly in English. Note: the issue marked Vol. 4, no. 3 is different than the previously-described Vol. 4, no. 3. Two issues share the same number.
- El Malcriado, Special, 1971 Oct. (Box 4)
  Issue is in English.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 5, nos. 1-15, 1972 Mar. 20 - 1972 Dec. 29 (Box 5)
  Issues are in English and Spanish. Vol. 5, no. 7 is missing.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 6, nos. 1-6, 1973 Jan. 12 - 1973 Mar. 23 (Box 5)
  Issues are in English and Spanish.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 6, nos. 7-25, 1973 Apr. 6 - 1973 Dec. 28 (Box 6)
  Issues 13-19 are in Spanish. Issues 7-12, 14, & 20-25 are in English. Vol. 6, no. 24 is missing.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 7, nos. 2-5, 1974 Feb. 22 - 1974 May 29 (Box 6)
  Issues are in English. Vol. 7, no. 1 is missing.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 7, nos. 10-11, 1974 Oct. 18 - 1974 Dec. 9 (Box 6)
  Issues are in English. Vol. 7, nos. 6-9 are missing.
- El Malcriado, Vol. 8, no. 1, 1975 Jan. - 1975 Feb. (Box 6)